# **NITIN DWIVEDI** (Sales Team Leader)

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated Sales person with extensive customer service and sales experience.

Outgoing sales professional with track record of driving increased sales, improving buying experience and elevating company profile with target market. Effectively demonstrate products and close sales. Persuasive in negotiating contracts and communicating in customer communications and building long term productive relationships.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Applect Systems Pvt. Ltd. (Meritnation) Delhi — Associate Sales Team Leader

(02/2020 to 08/2020)

 Connecting with parents and students and making them understand about the benefits of online study and learning packages. Converting potential customers into a revenue stream for the company.

### Aarika Trends Pvt. Ltd, Delhi — Sales Team Leader

(12/2019 to 01/2020)

• Handled a team of 5+ members with the target of connecting with different distributors to make them a continuous consumer for company products.

### **Infocom Network Ltd, Vasant Vihar** — Relationship Manager

(12/2018 to 12/2019)

 Managed approximately 90 clients maintaining consistent and good relationships with them since last year with full retention and recall value for Infocom and as an individual also.
 Complete handling of renewal, service and upgrade.

# INDIAMART INTERMESH LTD, Shahdara — Asst. Sales Manager (01/2017 to 12/2018)

 To contact manufacturers and make them understand about products/programs and achieve sales targets for the growth of the company.

#### FAITH MICRO SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD. East Delhi - Tr. Business Executive

(01/2016 to 01/2017)

 Experienced in dealing with large sized hospital authorities to understand their requirements and managing complete delivery after setting deals with sales leads. Also worked in stock management under dealers and distributorship. Having analytical approach to know about competition and executing sale tactics accordingly.

### **EDUCATION**

M.B.A | Marketing & HR | Axis college(UPTU) | 2015

B.Sc | P.C.M | CSJM University | 2012

XII Class | P.C.M | K.L S.V.M Inter College U.P | 2009

X Class | SCIENCE | K.L.S.V.M Inter College U.P | 2007

## **Key Skills**

- Sales.
- Product and Service sales.
- Customer relationship and Service.
- Negotiating the terms of an agreement and closing sales.
- Negotiating variations in price, delivery and specifications with company managers.
- Getting/Executing/Recording sales and order information and providing copies to the sales office.
- Recruitment, Training, Coaching of sales team.
- Sales report preparation.
- Digital Marketing certification

### Tools:

MSOffice suite, Outlook, Excel (for record keeping and reporting)